# **Toby Bessant - Curriculum Vitae**

Date of Birth 13/04/1998 Telephone 07538 955566

Email toby.bessant@tobybessant.co.uk

GitHub github.com/tobybessant Portfolio tobybessant.co.uk

## **Profile**

Progressive and client-focused full-stack developer experienced in producing robust applications across an array of technologies. Demonstrable understanding of software development fundamentals, in addition to a multitude of newer frameworks and libraries. Undertaken an industry placement year working under agile methodologies to integrate & automate business web-applications. Always exploring new ideas through tangible projects including a mobile tenancy communication platform, web-based multi-player typing game, and a noise-based procedural terrain generator.

# **Professional Experience**

2018–2019

# Business Applications Developer | A2Z Cloud

Placement year taken as part of my degree. Configured, automated, and integrated various Zoho and external business applications.

- Developed NodeJS middlewares to sync and map relational-database records to formats received by business applications.
- Hosted applications using AWS lambda.
- Used various REST API's & webhooks to connect services.
- Attended and ran weekly client meetings, both for requirements gathering and app demos.
- Took part in daily **scrum** meetings, even having the opportunity to run a scrum meeting when my manager was unavailable.

2015-2016

#### Customer Assisstant | The Regal Stowmarket

Part-time job during college to improve confidence and start earning some personal finances.

- Selling box office tickets, answering customer calls, working behind the bar
- Developed good communication skills due to small team of 3 at all times.
- Small team size meant I took part in marketing decisions and am proud to say that their growth led to plans of expansion after my departure.

## Education

2016–2020 | Computing & Games Development BSc (Hons), University of Plymouth.

Predicted to graduate with first-class honours

2014–2016 **A-Levels, Suffolk One Sixth-form College.** 

Computing: D, Sociology: B, Psychology: D, Ancient History AS: D

2009–2014 | GCSE's, Stradbroke High School.

English: B Core Science: B ICT: Pass
Maths: B Additional Science: B History: A
Religious Studies: A\* Business Studies: B Graphics: C

#### **Skills Profile**

As a result of my university degree I have experience developing in a wide range of languages, environments and disciplines. The first two years of my degree were centred around building a foundation for my programming skills, using C# and Java to demonstrate SOLID principles and implement design patterns to solve problems. As I have matured as a developer my primary interest has shifted towards full-stack web development. In my own time I started to teach myself about web development, and carried these skills into my final year at university. Since then, I have experience developing in JavaScript and TypeScript to produce APIs & persistence layers, communicating to both MongoDB and relational databases. My front-end development experience spans the use of VueJS and Angular8, for desktop web applications and native mobile applications (including a development pipeline using Ionic and Cordova). I have experience using Git in both individual and team settings, performing and receiving pull-requests and code reviews with my colleagues.

Between my second and third years of university, I was able to use the skills I had learnt in an industry environment - automating and integrating business web-applications for clients. This experience was valuable in helping me understand the wider impact that software has on businesses, in addition to putting my programming and system design skills into practice. I was given a high level of responsibility, directly demonstrating my solutions to clients over online meetings on a weekly basis. My placement gave me skills in programming and debugging in a web environment, in addition to working with APIs, databases, and building integration middleware. This middleware was often hosted on AWS which I would help configure. I would also be on the client support portal, emailing and calling clients to assist them with any problems they were experiencing. On a personal level, my placement year improved my confidence which in turn has helped with my ability to approach new challenges.

In addition to the skills outlined above, I have experience using C# to develop experience-based projects in Unity3D - allowing me to utilise my programming knowledge to make games, and VR experiences. During my final year of university I used C++ and OpenGL to build various graphics rendering applications; a model-loader to parse and render the data for 3D model files, and an application to procedurally generate & render virtual terrains using noise functions.

#### Interests

Outside of software development I have a keen interest in reading fiction books, particularly of the crime-fiction genre. I enjoy it because it provides a way for me to be analytical and test my problem solving abilities in an atypical way. In addition, I enjoy learning about ancient history - particularly Ancient Rome and Ancient Greece, as these eras of human history are responsible for many of our traditions today. In my spare time I play guitar, which feeds into an active interest in music - something which has had a large influence on my life.

# References

References available on request.